<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>express on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/express/</link>
    <description>Recent content in express on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 18:09:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/express/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Typescript and Socket.Io - Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://example.org/typescript/typescript-socket-io-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 18:09:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/typescript/typescript-socket-io-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Last Updated - 24th December, 2018
 Welcome friends! In this tutorial, we are going to be looking at how you can build a websocket based server using both TypeScript and Socket.io.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the following:
 What WebSockets are and why they are beneficial Building a Simple TypeScript WebSocket Server Building a Simple client to connect to our Server Two-way communication between our client and our server  WebSockets WebSockets are an awesome technology and I absolutely love playing around with them and creating real-time applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a RESTful API using Express and Typescript</title>
      <link>http://example.org/typescript/creating-rest-api-express-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:25:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/typescript/creating-rest-api-express-typescript/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we are going to be building a REST API using both express and TypeScript! This REST API will simply return a status depending on what API endpoint we hit using our HTTP Client.
Prerequisites You will require at least the following:
 TypeScript 2.8.1 The Yarn Package Manager ExpressJS  Our Project Layout So within our project, we are going to create a couple of incredibly simple endpoints that will simply return a few simple strings, depending on what HTTP verb is used to hit said route.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>