<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on CoTutorial</title>
    <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/series/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on CoTutorial</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id-ID</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:28:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cotutorial.github.io/series/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/get-involved/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:28:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/get-involved/</guid>
      <description>Do you fancy contributing back to the site or writing a few of your own tutorials? Fork this entire site from our public github repo, make some changes and then submit a pull request and I&amp;rsquo;ll review it and if it meets our standards, it&amp;rsquo;ll get pushed live to the site.
Authoring New Tutorials Authoring a new tutorial is simple with hugo. All you have to do is create a new file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:28:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/test/</guid>
      <description>What does this output?
console.log(&amp;#34;hi&amp;#34;)   
Sanguine Lapithae colla latus oracula ignibus Lorem markdownum coniugium levati sustollit tamen iuvenem, ignis aut paene quem per lacesse inde mihi: mea. Natalis aura, et undas hoc uberrima. Discedere maerenti virgine ut anilem opus, quae, enim sentit decurrere Nycteus sacrilegos Ecce numerandos, erat sententia. Quam nolet, e mortisque tegmine, laboris opus et domus. Plura audet; sensit unde Iunone summisque constiterant.
Alta hoc belli Lorem markdownum coniugium levati sustollit tamen iuvenem, ignis aut paene quem per lacesse inde mihi: mea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirect</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/redirect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:28:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/redirect/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Up</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/signup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:28:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/signup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 20:27:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>The Story: Originally started in December of 2014 this site began as a side hobby of mine and has quickly grown into one of the most successful side projects I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked upon. Since its conception it&amp;rsquo;s racked up well over 1,000,000 page views and it&amp;rsquo;s still growing.
It&amp;rsquo;s undergone many changes since it was first created and overall I&amp;rsquo;ve probably commited well over 1,000 hours towards the site and it&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>