<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gamedev on CoTutorial</title>
    <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/tags/gamedev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gamedev on CoTutorial</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id-ID</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:49:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cotutorial.github.io/tags/gamedev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Custom Diffuse Lighting Model in Unity - Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/unity/custom-diffuse-lighting-model-unity-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 18:49:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/unity/custom-diffuse-lighting-model-unity-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>If you are familiar with Unity 4, you may know that the default shader provided by it was based on a lighting model called the Lambertian reflectance. This article shows you how you can create a shader with a custom lighting model and explains the mathematics involved along with the implementation. The following diagram shows the same geometry rendered with a standard shader (right) and a diffuse Lambert one (left):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Books For Learning Game Development</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/best-books-learn-game-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 18:09:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/best-books-learn-game-dev/</guid>
      <description>This list is currently under construction
 In this article we will be looking at some of the best and most popular books you can buy should you wish to learn more about the art of game development.
Game development as a whole is quite a fragmented field, there are a wide number of game engines such as Unity and Unreal which abstract away the complexities of things like graphics rendering and physics engines and allow game developers to focus purely on game-play mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AABB Collision Detection Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/aabb-collision-detection-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 09:30:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/aabb-collision-detection-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>AABB Collision Detection or &#34;Axis-Aligned Bounding Box&#34; Collision detection as it stands for is the simplest form, or one of the simplest forms of collision detection that you can implement in a 2D game. If you have an object that is axis-aligned, ie. not rotated and doesn&#39;t need tight collision detection then AABB collision detection is the route you are going to want to take.
Implementing AABB Collision Detection in Java In order to be able to accurately perform Axis-Aligned Bounding Box collision detection you&#39;ll need at minimum the 4 following characteristics of the object you are wanting to make collidable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Shaders in OpenGL</title>
      <link>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/opengl/getting-started-with-shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 08:50:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cotutorial.github.io/gamedev/opengl/getting-started-with-shaders/</guid>
      <description>The modern OpenGL rendering pipeline rely heavily on shaders to process the huge amounts of data that a highly demanding program like a game requires. These shaders are typically written using the OpenGL Shading Language - GLSL, this language is very similar to C in syntax. Learning shaders is just about one of the most important things you can do if you are going to get into graphical programming as it enables you to control just about everything when it comes to rendering your models in a game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>