<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beginners on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/beginners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beginners on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:08:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/beginners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With VueJS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/getting-started-with-vuejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 20:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/getting-started-with-vuejs/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we are going to look at how you can setup your development environment so that you can get started writing your own VueJS.
We will be utilizing the vue-cli in order to start our project off and then we&amp;rsquo;ll be diving in and making a few edits, before finally building it using the same vue-cli.
Video Tutorial  A Simple Vue App Before I get started, it must be noted that you can get up and running really quickly with VueJS 2 in less than 30 lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To Web Development</title>
      <link>http://example.org/webdev/introduction-to-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 17:27:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/webdev/introduction-to-web-development/</guid>
      <description>Since it&amp;rsquo;s inception in the 90s the web has seen an explosion in the number and range of different web technologies used for building websites. However, if you have never created a website in your life then this can all be very daunting and initially offputting for someone wanting to take the plunge and get into web development seriously. In this introductory guide I&amp;rsquo;ll be helping to demystify some of the key terms and concepts that every web developer should know or be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuejs Components Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/vuejs-components-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 12:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/vuejs-components-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>This Tutorial builds off the starter application that we generated in the Getting Started with VueJS article.
 Video Tutorial This tutorial is also available in video format if you wish to watch it!
 Introduction In this tutorial, we are going to look at how you can work with components within your VueJS applications. We are going to start at looking at very simple components and then move on to your standard .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Components, Templates, and Props in Vue 2</title>
      <link>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/components-templates-and-props-vue-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/javascript/vuejs/components-templates-and-props-vue-2/</guid>
      <description>To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to make a component in Vue. First, we specify the component, like this:
Vue.component(&amp;#34;custom-article&amp;#34;, { template: ` &amp;lt;article&amp;gt; Our own custom article component!&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/article&amp;gt;` }); new Vue({ el: &amp;#34;#app&amp;#34; });  A component is a block of code that we give a custom name. This custom name can be anything we come up with, and it&amp;rsquo;s a single label for that entire block of code in the form of a custom HTML tag.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>